ALAN NAIR

INFO

E-mail alan.nair@ed.ac.uk

Github github.com/alannair

Website alannair.github.io

ABOUT ME

I landed in systems research after stumbling around various fields including software development, data science, and algorithmic trading while slowly realizing that my aptitude and natural interests align with computer systems. In particular, I love (and am experienced in) OS (esp. kernel hacking), and Computer Architecture.

EXPERIENCE

RESEARCH INTERN

Sep 2022 -Dec 2022

Intel Labs | Bengaluru, India

- Successfully scaled Data Access Monitoring to terabyte-scale workloads
- Incorporated page table based profiling schemes to DAMON in the Linux kernel
- Evaluated performance gains on terabyte-scale memory workloads

RESEARCH INTERN

May 2021 - Jan 2022

Intel Labs | Bengaluru, India (Remote)

- Built far memory support for serverless / FAAS environments using Linux kernel tools
- Integrated the far memory with the page fault handler
- Evaluated performance on standardized workloads
- Patented by Intel

TUTOR AND TEACHING ASSISTANT

Aug 2020 -Apr 2022

IIT Kanpur | Kanpur, India

- Tutored ESC101 (Fundamentals of Computing) for two batches of 36 firstyear students each over two semesters
- Conducted weekly tutorials, designed problems for labs and set questions for quizzes
- TA for CS330 (Operating Systems) to a batch of third-year students
- TA for CS335 (Compilers) to a batch of third-year students
- Designed assignments, graded guizzes and resolved students' doubts

QUANTITATIVE STRATEGIST

May 2020 - Jun 2020

Quadeye Securities LLC | Gurugram, India (Remote)

• Analysed real stock-price data and designed trading strategies

DATA SCIENCE / SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT INTERN

May 2019 - Jul 2019

Monet Networks | Gurugram, India

- Eye-Tracking and Detection over a webcam feed for a website
- Sentiment Analysis on tweets and user comments

EDUCATION

Ph.D 2023-

Dept. of Informatics, University of Edinburgh | Edinburgh, Scotland

• Supervised by Dr. Antonio Barbalace and Dr. Boris GROT

B.Tech + M.Tech (Dual Degree)

2017-2022

Dept. of CSE, IIT Kanpur | Kanpur, India

- CGPA: 8.7 / 10.0
- Masters Thesis: "Speeding Up Inference on CNNs for CPUs" was supervised by *Dr. Swarnendu Biswas* and done in collaboration with *Intel Labs, Bengaluru*

ACHIEVEMENTS

Rankings

- All India Rank 189 in JEE Advanced 2017
- All India Rank 1067 in JEE Mains 2017